http://www.slsa.sa.gov.au/privacy-statement

Skip to main content
We are open, find out what has changed.
Searching TROVE
Use and liability statement (Research service)
On this page
Our website and online applications (Library Guides, catalogue, Ask Us service and library management system) comply with the Information Privacy Principles (IPPS), Department of the Premier and Cabinet.
What is considered personal information?
Based on the IPPS personal information is defined as information, or an opinion, relating to a person, or the affairs of a person, whose identity is apparent or can be ascertained from the information or opinion.
Personal information we collect
The State Library website and online applications have online forms that collect the following information voluntarily from users:
When joining the State Library your name, current address, email and phone number are required to provide you with equitable access to materials and services.
Your name and email address are collected if you supply it under the following circumstances:
if you send us a message by email
you include your email address in an online form or survey
you subscribe to our e-news
use our Ask Us services
request or suggest items from the catalogue.
Update your personal information
Joining the State Library
To update or remove your library card registration information please visit us at the Information Desk or phone: (08) 8207 7250.
When you register for a library card, your registration lasts for three years. If your registration is not renewed, your personal information is deleted from our records. Upon registering you are given the option of receiving e-news updates from the library.
e-news subscription and events registering
To update your name or email address provided when you subscribed to our e-news or register for an event please contact:
Marketing
Email: slsamarketing@sa.gov.au
Phone: (08) 8207 7366
Fax (08) 8207 7247
GPO Box 419
Adelaide SA 5001
You can unsubscribe from the e-news here.
Use of your personal information
Your personal information is used and retained for the purposes of the services you subscribed to.
No attempt will be made to permanently record the materials or services used. Our library management system will record materials used while they are in use for security purposes, but does not keep a record of the user after the material is returned.
Storing your personal information
Keeping your personal information secure is important to us. We keep your data securely stored on our web-server ensuring it is not misused, lost or altered without your permission. Our staff who undertake services for you or engage with you are committed to keeping your information confidential.
Disclosure of your personal information
The State Library does not disclose personal information for any purpose other than what the personal information was gathered for. Exceptions to this disclosure statement are listed in the IPPS, which we adhere to and comply with.
Third-party applications
The State Library provides some services and customer engagement via third-party products such as event bookings, online surveys and social media.
The personal information collected for these services and engagement is strictly used for the provision of the service or engagement. No personal information is gathered or stored elsewhere without the prior agreement of the user.
Event bookings and surveys
When you register for an event, your details are retained in the event booking application and not transferred to our library management system. When you undertake an online survey, you are given the opportunity to receive further information or remain anonymous.
Social media
User's of social media applications should make themselves aware of the privacy policy of each. The State Library does not retain personal information from social media applications.
Collection of non-personal information
Our website and online applications automatically collect information about each user visit to the site via Google Analytics, cookies, and clickstream data. This data provides useful information and statistics about a user's online experience without identifying them. The type of information collected includes:
user's IP address
date and time of the visit
pages access and documents downloaded
the previous site visited
type of browser used.
Why we collect non-personal information
This information shows us how our sites and online applications are being used and help us improve them to make your visit useful and enjoyable. No attempt will be made to identify users or their browsing activities except in the unlikely event of an investigation where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect our web-server logs. This information is analysed annually to determine website and online application usage.
When you leave our website and online applications
The State Library website and online applications contain links to a large number of other websites. When a user has clicked on a link to another site, they leave the State Library site and are no longer protected by the State Library's privacy conditions.
Takedown policy
The State Library's takedown policy allows you to request the removal of material on any State Library website where you as a copyright owner have not given permission, or that relates to other specific matters.
This privacy statement is periodically reviewed in line with the ongoing development of the website and other services.
Chat with a librarian
